

Jahir Fabian Fiquitiva Ricaurte

jahir.dev

@jahirfiquitiva

About

I am a passionate and creative full-stack software engineer based in Colombia, with five (5) years of professional experience, aiming on crafting great-looking software products. I focus on details, accessibility and writing maintainable code.

I consider myself a proactive worker and learner, being able to work with a team, under the terms of respect and support, and helping build diverse, inclusive and safe and sound workplaces. I am always eager for challenges where I can gain new skills or improve the existent ones.

■ Experience

Software Technologist @ Matter Supply Co.

Sep 2020 ~ Nov 2022 - Full-time

- Developed features and built user interface components for a client's online store with presence in 5 countries.
- Refactored an android app to a modern codebase, aiming to make it more user friendly and flexible by showcasing content from a CMS.

Skills: NextJS, TypeScript, Styled Components, Contentful, Shopify. Android, Jetpack, Kotlin, Coroutines, ViewModels, DataBinding.

Associate Professor @ Universidad de Antioquia

Sep 2021 ~ Oct 2021 - Seasonal

- Participated in the Colombian government program "Misión TIC 2022"
- Had the opportunity to teach about modern full-stack development tools to about 50 people from different ages and backgrounds.
- Topics covered in classes: Git, HTML5, JavaScript, React, NodeJS, MongoDB and Express.

Skills: teaching, mentoring, team work.

Chief Technology Officer @ Synaptikö S.L

Feb 2021 ~ Jun 2021 - Freelance

- Led a team of 3 people building and developing a platform for providing mental health care services in Spain.
- Had the responsibility of taking decisions on architecture planning, UI and UX design and feature development.

Skills: leadership, architecture, NextJS, TypeScript, Chakra UI, Firebase.

Technical Development Lead @ BPSmart S.A.S

Jan 2020 ~ Aug 2020 - Full-time

- Led a team of 6 junior developers building a Business Process Outsourcing platform with smart solutions such as debt collection, sales and customer service.
- As a lead, I had the opportunity to contribute to team growth by guiding members on a learning process and helping them improve their skillset.
- Developed part of multiple software services and software products participating in both frontend and backend engineering.

Skills: leadership, architecture, career path, React, React Material Web Components, Firebase, Google Cloud App Engine and Cloud Storage.

Full Stack Developer @ Servex S.A.C.

Sep 2018 ~ Dec 2019 - Full-time

- Built multiple frontend apps and backend services for sales, payments and debt management tools.
- Created a flexible conversational artificial-intelligence powered bot for contacting clients as part of said services.

Skills: JavaScript, React, NodeJS, MongoDB, Express, Python, Rasa, Docker.

Mobile Developer @ Vezio Inc.

Oct 2017 ~ Jan 2019 - Part-time

- Developed the android app for the company product from scratch. It was a platform for tracking employees working hours and activities.
- Worked on both user interface design and functional features to make it match the existing companion desktop and web apps.
- Also created an initial iOS app with features and design similar to the android app, achieving a complete multi-platform product.

Skills: Android, Kotlin, Material Design, ViewModels, Swift.

Education

Computer Science BSc.

Universidad Pedagógica y Tecnológica de Colombia UPTC Sogamoso, Colombia – 2015 ~ 2021

A Languages

Spanish (Native) ~ English (Fluent)

